<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <id>http://lelylan.com/</id>
  <title>Lelylan - reThink your house</title>
  <updated>2011-10-15T22:00:00Z</updated>
  <link rel="alternate" href="http://lelylan.com/"/>
  <link rel="self" href="http://lelylan.com/blog/feed.xml"/>
  <author>
    <name>Lelylan Team</name>
    <uri>http://lelylan.com</uri>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <id>tag:lelylan.com,2011-10-16:/blog/why/</id>
    <title type="html">The connected house</title>
    <published>2011-10-15T22:00:00Z</published>
    <updated>2011-10-15T22:00:00Z</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" href="http://lelylan.com/blog/why/"/>
    <content type="html">&lt;div class="article"&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;
    Lelylan is a project called to life by the need of solving technological limitations that 
    home automation (aka domotics) is facing today.
    Nowadays our houses are furnished with numerous devices like appliances, lighting systems, 
    alarms, irrigation systems, smoke and gas detectors, heating, cooling, audio, video systems 
    and much more. There is only a problem, well, a big problem: those devices use different 
    standards and they can't easily communicate with each other.
  &lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;
    &lt;strong&gt;Lelylan has 3 goals&lt;/strong&gt;
  &lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;blockquote&gt;
    &lt;ol&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Connect your house to the web with a clear and simple set of web services.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Enable all devices to communicate with each other.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Allow everybody to create new services on top of Lelylan, so that we can speed 
          up innovation in this field.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;/blockquote&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;
    To make the concept clear, let's think at some of the most important web services available 
    today, like Facebook and Twitter. They offer APIs to access our social graph or our micro 
    blogging data. In the same way, Lelylan wants to define a set of simple, clear and consistent
    APIs to access all resources interacting with your house through the web.
  &lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;
    What we aim to do is to map every device to a unique URI which will provide control over it. 
    When such a connection is done, technological limitations disappear and devices become 
    identifiable only through their functionalities.
  &lt;/p&gt;  

  &lt;p&gt;
    For the first time you have a real chance to change how home automation works. If you are one 
    of those crazy innovators, &lt;a href="/collaborations/"&gt;write us about your ideas&lt;/a&gt;.
  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;/div&gt;</content>
  </entry>
</feed>
